---
title: "WB Clerkship Exam 2019 Shift - 1 (GS) Mock Test"
subject: "WB Clerkship"
topic: "General Studies(40 Questions)"
questions:
  - question: "Mahatma Gandhi had first started his non-violent non-cooperation movement in"
    options:
      - "UK"
      - "South Africa"
      - "India"
      - "Zimbabwe"
    answer: "South Africa"

  - question: "The India-Bangladesh Border is guarded on the Indian side by"
    options:
      - "The Indian Army"
      - "Border Security Forces (BSF)"
      - "CRPF"
      - "Indo-Tibetan Border Police"
    answer: "Border Security Forces (BSF)"

  - question: "Which one of the following states of India has lost its special status due to abolition of Article 370?"
    options:
      - "Manipur"
      - "Jammu and Kashmir"
      - "Nagaland"
      - "Sikkim"
    answer: "Jammu and Kashmir"

  - question: "Mahatma Gandhi was assassinated on 30th January"
    options:
      - "1947"
      - "1948"
      - "1949"
      - "1950"
    answer: "1948"

  - question: "The Rafale deal relates to the acquisition of"
    options:
      - "helicopters"
      - "fighter planes"
      - "submarines"
      - "long range missiles"
    answer: "fighter planes"

  - question: "Gautam Buddha was born in"
    options:
      - "Kapilavastu"
      - "Sarnath"
      - "Bodh Gaya"
      - "Lumbini"
    answer: "Lumbini"

  - question: "Vidyasagar's birthplace 'Birsingha' village is in"
    options:
      - "Hooghly district"
      - "Nadia district"
      - "West Medinipur district"
      - "Howrah district"
    answer: "West Medinipur district"

  - question: "Who among the following persons is a Boxer?"
    options:
      - "Dibyendu Barua"
      - "Chand Ram"
      - "Manju Rani"
      - "Dipa Karmakar"
    answer: "Manju Rani"

  - question: "Jaideep Mukherjee represented India in"
    options:
      - "Tennis"
      - "Badminton"
      - "Cricket"
      - "Football"
    answer: "Tennis"

  - question: "Which one of the following rivers does not flow across the India-Bangladesh border?"
    options:
      - "The Ganges"
      - "Teesta"
      - "Atrayee"
      - "Damodar"
    answer: "Damodar"

  - question: "Which one of the following items is sought to be banned for protection of environment?"
    options:
      - "Jute bags"
      - "Plastic bags"
      - "Paper bags"
      - "Cloth bags"
    answer: "Plastic bags"

  - question: "Which one of the following states is not a Member of SAARC?"
    options:
      - "Bangladesh"
      - "Myanmar"
      - "Sri Lanka"
      - "Nepal"
    answer: "Myanmar"

  - question: "Which one of the following is not an independent state?"
    options:
      - "Australia"
      - "Scotland"
      - "Belgium"
      - "Spain"
    answer: "Scotland"

  - question: "S-400 missiles are being acquired from"
    options:
      - "Sweden"
      - "UK"
      - "Russia"
      - "USA"
    answer: "Russia"

  - question: "President Donald Trump succeeded"
    options:
      - "Bill Clinton"
      - "Barack Obama"
      - "Colin Powell"
      - "George Bush Jr."
    answer: "Barack Obama"

  - question: "Who is the present President of France?"
    options:
      - "Nicolas Sarkozy"
      - "Jean Monnet"
      - "Emmanuel Macron"
      - "Francois Hollande"
    answer: "Emmanuel Macron"

  - question: "Lionel Messi hails from"
    options:
      - "Brazil"
      - "Argentina"
      - "Bolivia"
      - "Portugal"
    answer: "Argentina"

  - question: "The Magsaysay Award (2019) in Journalism was given to"
    options:
      - "Swapan Dasgupta"
      - "Raveesh Kumar"
      - "Arnab Goswami"
      - "Ravindra Kumar"
    answer: "Raveesh Kumar"

  - question: "Who among the following was awarded the Nobel Prize in Literature in 2019?"
    options:
      - "Peter Handke"
      - "Bob Dylan"
      - "Olga Tokarczuk"
      - "Salman Rushdie"
    answer: "Peter Handke"

  - question: "Except Hong Kong, how many other Special Administrative Regions (SARs) are there in China?"
    options:
      - "2"
      - "1"
      - "3"
      - "None of the above"
    answer: "1"

  - question: "Which of the following team won the Cricket World Cup in 2019?"
    options:
      - "South Africa"
      - "England"
      - "New Zealand"
      - "India"
    answer: "England"

  - question: "The 2016 Olympic games were held in"
    options:
      - "London"
      - "Rio-de-Janeiro"
      - "Moscow"
      - "Mexico City"
    answer: "Rio-de-Janeiro"

  - question: "How many seats are there in Lok Sabha?"
    options:
      - "540"
      - "543"
      - "545"
      - "550"
    answer: "545"

  - question: "Who is currently the Chairman of IMF?"
    options:
      - "Christine Lagarde"
      - "Kristalina Georgieva"
      - "Jean Claude Juncker"
      - "Donald Tusk"
    answer: "Kristalina Georgieva"

  - question: "The UN Human Rights Commission has its headquarters in"
    options:
      - "Geneva"
      - "Washington"
      - "Paris"
      - "London"
    answer: "Geneva"

  - question: "Before becoming the president of India, Pranab Mukherjee never held the post of"
    options:
      - "Defence Minister"
      - "Finance Minister"
      - "Minister for Railways"
      - "Minister for External Affairs"
    answer: "Minister for Railways"

  - question: "The battle of Plassey was fought in"
    options:
      - "1757"
      - "1758"
      - "1857"
      - "1858"
    answer: "1757"

  - question: "The first Asian games were held in"
    options:
      - "Jakarta"
      - "New Delhi"
      - "Colombo"
      - "Bangkok"
    answer: "New Delhi"

  - question: "The Easter Sunday suicide bombings in 2019 had taken place in"
    options:
      - "Christ Church"
      - "Colombo"
      - "Bradford"
      - "Jerusalem"
    answer: "Colombo"

  - question: "Who is the author of the book 'The Third Pillar'?"
    options:
      - "Amartya Sen"
      - "Padma Desai"
      - "Raghuram Rajan"
      - "Jagdish Bhagwati"
    answer: "Raghuram Rajan"

  - question: "Who won the World Championship in Badminton (women's single) in 2019?"
    options:
      - "Sania Mirza"
      - "Saina Nehwal"
      - "P. V. Sindhu"
      - "Nozomi Okuhara"
    answer: "P. V. Sindhu"

  - question: "Khudiram Bose was hanged in"
    options:
      - "Medinipur"
      - "Dum Dum Central Jail"
      - "Muzaffarpur"
      - "Presidency Jail, Kolkata"
    answer: "Muzaffarpur"

  - question: "Where does the Dalai Lama live?"
    options:
      - "Mussoorie"
      - "Rumtek Monastery"
      - "Tawang"
      - "Mcleodganj, Dharamshala"
    answer: "Mcleodganj, Dharamshala"

  - question: "How many districts are there in West Bengal?"
    options:
      - "21"
      - "19"
      - "24"
      - "22"
    answer: "24"

  - question: "Balakot is in"
    options:
      - "India's north-east"
      - "Pakistan's north-west"
      - "Afghanistan"
      - "Iran-Afghanistan border"
    answer: "Pakistan's north-west"

  - question: "Fiji is in"
    options:
      - "the Asia-Pacific region"
      - "the North Atlantic region"
      - "North Africa"
      - "South America"
    answer: "the Asia-Pacific region"

  - question: "Which one of the following is not a Union Territory?"
    options:
      - "Chandigarh"
      - "Andaman and Nicobar Islands"
      - "Puducherry"
      - "Tripura"
    answer: "Tripura"

  - question: "The Howdy Modi programme was held in"
    options:
      - "Los Angeles"
      - "New York"
      - "Houston"
      - "Washington"
    answer: "Houston"

  - question: "Who among the following persons was not a famous sculptor?"
    options:
      - "Jogen Chowdhury"
      - "Nandalal Bose"
      - "Ramkinkar Baij"
      - "Tarasankar Bandhopadhyay"
    answer: "Tarasankar Bandhopadhyay"

  - question: "Greta Thunberg is"
    options:
      - "an Actor"
      - "a Tennis player"
      - "an Environmental activist"
      - "a Human Rights activist"
    answer: "an Environmental activist"

---